<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.6">
  <compounddef id="a00022" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_Documentation_YarnSpinner-Programming_README</compoundname>
    <title>Yarn Spinner Programming README</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><heading level="2">Style Guide</heading>
</para><para><computeroutput>Inline Code</computeroutput> contain short snippets of code for your project <verbatim>Code Blocks contain segments or chunks of code for your project
</verbatim></para><para><bold>Bold indicate actions (Select menu item, copying file, etc.)</bold></para><para>***Bold italic text indicates emphasis***</para><para><blockquote><para>Blockquotes contain essential information</para><para></para></blockquote></para><para><heading level="2">Introduction</heading>
</para><para>This document lists the other document that comprise the Programming documentation for <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner. Programming <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner is intended to mean coding C# to achieve the goals set out in <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Dialogue to meet the proudction requirements of producing a game. The game can be produced using any engine, however for now we only document using Unity.</para><para><heading level="2">Building</heading>
</para><para>The <ref refid="a00119" kindref="compound">Building</ref> assists you in compiling the <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner software. You may need to build <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner yourself, particularly if you wish to test out certain code or use tools (such as ../YarnSpinner-Dialogue/Localization.md &quot;Localiisation&quot;.</para><para><heading level="2">Extending</heading>
</para><para>The default <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner code may not provide enough functionality for your game, so you will need to extend it by adding your own functions. The <ref refid="a00120" kindref="compound">Extending</ref> documentation provides an example on how to create custom C# code to integrate with <ulink url="../YarnSpinner-Dialogue/">Yarn Dialogue</ulink></para><para><heading level="3">API Reference</heading>
</para><para>The <ulink url="https://thesecretlab.github.io/YarnSpinner/html/">API Reference</ulink> is available online for the current release. It&apos;s possible to use the build script to create your own. See the <ref refid="a00119" kindref="compound">Building</ref> documentation for information on how to do this. </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
