<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.6">
  <compounddef id="a00028" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_Documentation_YarnSpinner-Unity_YarnSpinner-with-Unity-StepByStep</compoundname>
    <title>Step by Step to Using Yarn Spinner in your Unity game</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><heading level="3">Style Guide</heading>
</para><para><computeroutput>Inline Code</computeroutput> contain short snippets of code for your project <verbatim>Code Blocks contain segments or chunks of code for your project
</verbatim></para><para><bold>Bold indicate actions (Select menu item, copying file, etc.)</bold></para><para>***Bold italic text indicates emphasis***</para><para><blockquote><para>Blockquotes contain essential information</para><para></para></blockquote></para><para><heading level="2">Tutorial</heading>
</para><para><blockquote><para>***Note:*** This tutorial assumes that you know a little bit about <ulink url="http://www.unity3d.com">Unity</ulink>. In particular, it is helpful that you know how to get around the Unity editor, how to work with game objects, and how to write scripts in C#. If you don&apos;t know these things, please refer to <ulink url="http://unity3d.com/learn">Unity&apos;s documentation</ulink>.</para><para></para></blockquote></para><para><heading level="2">Step by Step</heading>
</para><para><heading level="3">Introducing <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner</heading>
</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner is designed to be easy to work with in Unity. It makes no assumptions about how your game presents dialogue to the player, or about how the player chooses their responses.</para><para>To introduce <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner, we&apos;ll create an empty Unity project, and then build it from the ground up to run a sample conversation. If you&apos;d first like to see the finished project, <ulink url="https://github.com/thesecretlab/YarnSpinner/releases">download Yarn Spinner</ulink> and open the <ulink url="https://github.com/thesecretlab/YarnSpinner/tree/master/Unity">Unity folder</ulink> in the Unity editor. To build a standalone version of this loaded project, skip to the end of this documentation.</para><para>To use <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner, you use three classes that will exist in the <computeroutput><ref refid="a00129" kindref="compound">Yarn.Unity</ref></computeroutput> namespace.</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput>, which is responsible for loading and running your dialogue script;</para></listitem><listitem><para>A subclass of <computeroutput>DialogueUIBehaviour</computeroutput>, which is reponsible for displaying the lines and dialogue choices to the player; and</para></listitem><listitem><para>A subclass of <computeroutput>VariableStorageBehaviour</computeroutput>, which is responsible for storing the state of the conversation.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>To create your subclasses of <computeroutput>DialogueUIBehaviour</computeroutput> and <computeroutput>VariableStorageBehaviour</computeroutput>, you&apos;ll need to add the following code to the top of your C# code: <verbatim>using Yarn.Unity;
</verbatim></para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> dialogue is created using the <ulink url="http://github.com/infiniteammoinc/Yarn">Yarn Editor</ulink>, and the resulting dialogue is stored as <computeroutput>.json</computeroutput> assets in the Unity project. If you are using Linux and wish to use the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Editor, you will first need to <ulink url="https://nwjs.io/downloads/">install</ulink> or build <ulink url="https://nwjs.io/">NW.js</ulink> then attempt to build the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Editor. <bold>NOTE AT THIS STAGE, BUILDING NW.JS HAS NOT BEEN ATTEMPTED BY US AND MAY SET YOUR COMPUTER ON FIRE</bold>.</para><para>The <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> dialogue files can be stored anywhere inside the project hierarchy - you simply provide add them to the <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput>&apos;s inspector. You can also call <computeroutput>AddScript</computeroutput> on the <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput> at runtime; this is useful for cases such as spawning a character who comes with additional dialogue - all that needs to happen is the character then pass their <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> script to the <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput>.</para><para><heading level="3">Create the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> conversations</heading>
</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>In the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Editor, <bold>Create a new conversation</bold>, and save it as a JSON file. (Alternatively, if you already have a dialogue file you&apos;d like to use, go ahead and use that instead!). For information on how to create a <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> conversation, please refer to the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Editor site.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="3">Create the Unity project</heading>
</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Launch Unity</bold>, and <bold>create a new project</bold>. The name of the project doesn&apos;t matter.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="3">Import the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner package.</heading>
</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para>**<ulink url="https://github.com/thesecretlab/YarnSpinner/releases">Import YarnSpinner.unitypackage</ulink>** into your project.</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner is composed of a <computeroutput>yarnspinner.dll</computeroutput> file, and a couple of supporting scripts for Unity. This dll file does the heavy lifting involved in parsing your <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> files, and executing them.</para><para>To show <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> dialogue in your game, you will need to add it to your project as well.</para></listitem><listitem><para><bold>Copy your <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> JSON file</bold> into your project.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>You&apos;re now ready to start using <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner!</para><para><heading level="3">Load your conversation with <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput></heading>
</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> conversations are loaded and managed by a <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput> object. This object is responsible for loading and parsing your <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> <computeroutput>.json</computeroutput> files. It also runs the script when it&apos;s told to - for example, when you walk up to a character in your game and talk to them.</para><para>We&apos;ll start by creating an empty object, and then we&apos;ll add the <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput> component to it.</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Create a new empty game object</bold>.</para></listitem><listitem><para><bold>Rename it to &quot;Dialogue Runner&quot;</bold>.</para></listitem><listitem><para>With the Dialogue Runner object selected, <bold>open the Component menu</bold>, and choose <bold>Scripts → <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner → Dialogue Runner</bold>.</para><para>Next you need to add the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> files that you want to show. The Dialogue runner can load multiple <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> files at the same time. The only requirement is that <bold>no nodes are allowed to have the same name</bold>. (This is a requirement that may change in the future.)</para></listitem><listitem><para><bold>Drag your <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> JSON file into the <computeroutput>Source Text</computeroutput> array.</bold></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="3">Display your conversation with <computeroutput>DialogueUI</computeroutput></heading>
</para><para>Your game&apos;s dialogue needs to be shown to the user. Additionally, you need a way to let the player choose what their reaction is going to be.</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner makes no assumptions about how you want to handle your dialogue&apos;s UI. Want to present as simple list of options? That&apos;s fine. Want a fancy Mass Effect style radial menu? Totally cool. Want a totally bonkers gesture-based UI with a countdown timer? Oh man that would be sweet.</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner leaves all of the work of actually presenting the conversation up to you; all it&apos;s responsible for is delivering the lines that the player should see, and notifying <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner about what response the user selected.</para><para><ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner comes with an example script that uses Unity&apos;s UI system. It&apos;s a good place to start.</para><para><heading level="3">Store your conversation state with a <computeroutput>VariableStorageBehaviour</computeroutput></heading>
</para><para>There&apos;s one last necessary component. As you play through a conversation, you&apos;ll probably want to record the user&apos;s choices somewhere. <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner doesn&apos;t care about the details of how you save your game state; instead, it just expects you to give it an object that conforms to a ***<ulink url="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/dotnet/csharp/programming-guide/interfaces/index">C# interface</ulink>)***, which defines methods like &quot;set variable&quot; and &quot;get value of variable&quot;.</para><para>The simplest implementation of this is one that just keeps your variables in memory, but it&apos;s pretty straightforward to adapt an existing save game system to use it.</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Create a new game object</bold>, and add the <computeroutput><ref refid="a00083" kindref="compound">ExampleVariableStorage</ref></computeroutput> script to it.</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para>Or:</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Create a new game object</bold>, and add a new script to it. Make this script subclass <computeroutput>VariableStorageBehaviour</computeroutput>, and the implement the <computeroutput>SetNumber</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>GetNumber</computeroutput>, <computeroutput>Clear</computeroutput>, and <computeroutput>ResetToDefaults</computeroutput> methods.</para></listitem><listitem><para>Once you&apos;ve done that, <bold>drag this new object into the Dialoge Runner&apos;s <computeroutput>Variable Storage</computeroutput> slot.</bold></para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="3">Run your conversation</heading>
</para><para>There&apos;s only one thing left to do: <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Spinner just needs to know what node in the <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> file to start from. It will default to &quot;Start&quot;, but you can override it.</para><para><itemizedlist>
<listitem><para><bold>Change the Dialogue Runner&apos;s <computeroutput>Start Node</computeroutput></bold> to the <bold>name of the node you&apos;d like to start run.</bold></para></listitem><listitem><para>Finally, <bold>run the game.</bold> The conversation will play!</para></listitem></itemizedlist>
</para><para><heading level="3">Respond to commands with <computeroutput>YarnCommand</computeroutput></heading>
</para><para>In <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref>, you can create <emphasis>commands</emphasis> that tell your game to do something. For example, if you want a character to move to a certain point on the screen, you might have a command that looks like this: <verbatim>&lt;&lt;move Sally exit&gt;&gt;
</verbatim></para><para>For this to work, the game object named &quot;Sally&quot; needs to have a script component attached to it, and one of those scripts needs to have a method that looks like this: <verbatim>[YarnCommand(&quot;move&quot;)]
public void MoveCharacter(string destinationName) {
    // move to the destination
}
</verbatim></para><para>When <ref refid="a00045" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> encounters a command that contains two or more words, it looks for a game object with the same name as the second word (&quot;Sally&quot;, in the above example), and then searches that object&apos;s scripts for any method that has a <computeroutput>YarnCommand</computeroutput> with the same name as the first word (in this case, &quot;move&quot;).</para><para>Any further words in the command are passed as string parameters to the method (&quot;exit&quot;, in this case, which is used as the <computeroutput>destinationName</computeroutput> parameter)</para><para>Note that <bold>all</bold> parameters must be strings. <computeroutput>DialogueRunner</computeroutput> will throw an error if it finds a method that has parameters of any other type. It&apos;s up to your method to convert the strings into other types, like numbers.</para><para><heading level="3">Finishing up</heading>
</para><para>Save the project</para><para>Build a stand alone </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
