<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8' standalone='no'?>
<doxygen xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="compound.xsd" version="1.8.6">
  <compounddef id="a00010" kind="page">
    <compoundname>md_Documentation_YarnSpinner-Dialogue_README</compoundname>
    <title>Writing Yarn Dialogue - README</title>
    <detaileddescription>
<para><heading level="2">Introducing <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Dialogue</heading>
</para><para><ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Dialogue is designed for Authors who have little or no programming knowledge. It makes no assumptions about how your game presents dialogue to the player, or about how the player chooses their responses. These tasks are left to the game production team, using programming and design tools such as Unity3D and C#.</para><para><heading level="3">Simple Example Dialogue</heading>
</para><para>In <ref refid="a00118" kindref="compound">our simple example</ref>, we will create a very simple Dialogue that demonstrates the very basic usage of <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref>.</para><para><heading level="3">Complex Example Dialogue</heading>
</para><para>In the <ref refid="a00117" kindref="compound">complex example</ref>, we will create a slightly more complex Dialogue to the simple example above. This example demonstrates more advanced possibilities that exist within telling stories in a narrative game environment.</para><para><heading level="3">Localisation</heading>
</para><para>Our localisation document describes how localisation, or translating the text into other languages, takes place. <blockquote><para>***Note:*** At the moment, it is a requirement that a programmer run a special tool across the Dialogue to produce the files to be translated.</para><para></para></blockquote></para><para><heading level="3">General Usage</heading>
</para><para>We have a page of <ref refid="a00116" kindref="compound">general usage</ref>, describing many further features of the <ref refid="a00040" kindref="compound">Yarn</ref> Language. It also containins small Dialogue snippets as well as tips and suggestions you might find useful. </para>    </detaileddescription>
  </compounddef>
</doxygen>
